MUHAMMAD FAHEEM

Civil Engineer



+923062429014



mohammadfaheem514@gmail.com



A-876 Gulshan-e-Hadeed Phase-2, Karachi.

OBJECTIVE

Dedicated and detailed-oriented civil engineer with a experience of planning and execution of site work in power plant. To make a position for myself in a reputed company in which I can use engineering and technical skills and leadership qualities that can contribute to the company's growth as well as enhance my knowledge by exploring new things.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Assistant Civil Engineer at BQPS III 900MW Combine Cylce Power Plant

Prima Energie



08/2020 – present

- Supervise the work of excavation, backfilling, dig ditches and trenches and compaction to grade specification.
- Handled all issues with relative ease by implementing best practices and applying critical thinking skills to find best solutions.
- Work collaboratively with multi-disciplinary team and Play a key role in quality control and evaluated incoming materials for quality and amounts ordered.
- Planning and Execution of works as per design & drawing and execute the work to meet quality, budgetary and scheduling requirements.
- Watched the construction of structure, pile foundation and placement of steel structure and machinery for combine cycle power plant.

Trainee Engineer at Shipyard Syncrolift Ship lift and Transfer System

Makkah Engineering



02/2020 - 03/2020

- Scheduled labour, ordered materials and coordinated with other contractors to complete the projects.
- Recorded daily events and activities in site diary to evaluate the process and improve productivity.
- Watched the construction of jetty, deck slab, rail alignment and platform placement for ship lift and transferring system.

Internee at Indus Hospital

AAA Consultants



04/2019 - 05/2019

- Understanding of structural and architectural drawing and implementation on the site.
- Understanding of BBS from structural drawing.



EDUCATION

B.E in Civil Engineering Sir Syed University of **Engineering and Technology**



1/2016 - 12/2019

SKILLS

Microsoft Office

AutoCAD

(Certified by Digi skills)

Etabs

EXPERTISE

- Proficient in giving the best result in under pressure.
- Ability to prioritize and handle multiple tasks.
- Proficient in planning and execution.
- Efficient in critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make good decisions.
- Proficient in leading the team from front.